MAGED BADR

Website: magedbadr.com

■ 9641 Simpson Place NW
Edmonton, Alberta, Canada T6R 0T8

① +1 587.938.2425 **≤** <u>contact@magedbadr.com</u>



MEDICAL LABORATORY PROFESSIONAL

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Performance-driven, committed and patient-oriented healthcare professional, offering comprehensive experience in providing medical laboratory assistance. Skilled at collecting specimens for medical examinations.

diagnosis, recording medical history and examination results and performing laboratory procedures. Armed with broad knowledge of laboratory terminologies, protocols and guidelines; complemented with background in supporting physicians during critical medical procedures. Proficient with Microsoft Office Suite, electronic medical records and laboratory equipment. Multilingual in English, Arabic, and French.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Results Laboratory Analysis Continuous Quality Improvement Clinical Documentation Pre- and Post-examination Administration Organizational Collaboration and Team Building Medical Procedures and Processes

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Medical Laboratory Assistant, Canadian Society for Medical Laboratory Science (CSMLS)

Medical Laboratory Assistant Training Program: 2018

Northern Alberta Institute of Technology – Edmonton, AB, Canada

Post-graduate Diploma in Total Quality Management: 2013

American University – Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor of Science in Microbiology and Chemistry: 2001

Benha University – Banha, Egypt

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DYNALIFE MEDICAL LABS - EDMONTON, AB

Medical Laboratory Assistant (Mobile Collection Team)

2021-

Now

- Collected and prepared samples and blood components from patients for laboratory analysis.
- Administration of electrocardiogram and laboratory tests, including pre- and post-examination phases.
- Maintenance of work area and equipment.
- Documentation of all activities, recorded results and data retrieval.
- Observed strict compliance with set-forth health and safety guidelines.

ALBERTA PRECISION LABS. / ALBERTA HEALTH SERVICES
MCLENNAN HOSPITAL in MCLENNAN, AB, CANADA
LACOMBE HOSPITAL, in LACOMBE, AB, CANADA
UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA HOSPITAL in EDMONTON, AB, CANADA

Medical Laboratory Assistant

2019-

Now

- Observed strict compliance with set-forth health and safety guidelines.
- Collected and prepared samples and blood components from patients for laboratory analysis.
- Efficiently handled and processed specimens in line with institution's methodologies.
- Administration of electrocardiogram and laboratory tests, including pre- and post-examination phases.
- Took charge of clarifying instructions for patients' tests and coordinating with physicians and patients regarding procedures.
- Maintenance of work area and equipment.

Date: From September 2014 till March 2016.

Position: Executive Manger.

Company: STAR Laboratory, Banha, Egypt.

- Developing and implementing various sales and distribution channels for the laboratory services.
- Communicate with all stakeholders (internal and external) to achieve positive results.
- Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily for Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time.
- Plan and implement all marketing strategies aimed at attaining sales, market share and profitability growth for the laboratory within the overall marketing budgets.
- Define the monthly and annual target.
- Participate in planning and budgeting processes; personnel and equipment need; develop and monitor laboratory budget.
- Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical, Hematological, Hormonal & PCR tests which are available in Banha Center units.
- Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- Replying doctors' inquiries.

Date: From July 2013 till September 2014.

Position: Banha Branch Manager.

Company: Al Borg Laboratories, Egypt.

Website: www.alborglab.com

Tasks: as follows:

- Developing and implementing various sales and distribution channels for the laboratory services.

- Communicate with all stakeholders (internal and external) to achieve positive results.
- Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily for Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time.
- Plan and implement all marketing strategies aimed at attaining sales, market share and profitability growth for the laboratory within the overall marketing budgets.
- Define the monthly and annual target.
- Participate in planning and budgeting processes; personnel and equipment need; develop and monitor laboratory budget. 7 Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical and Hematological tests which are available in Branch units.
- Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- Replying doctors' inquiries.

Date: From November 2004 till July 2013.

Position: Medical Analysis Specialist. **Company: Al** Borg Laboratories, Egypt.

Website: www.alborglab.com Banha Branch.

Tasks: as follows:

- Performing Scientifically, Technical and Professional analysis in Branch Committed Rules applicable in medical analysis field and the foundation Rules developed for good performance of the company.
- Commitment Work is 7 hours Daily for Six Days Weekly for at least 42 hours Weekly with Full-time.
- Clarifying the instructions for each analysis professionally for patients.
- Taking samples from patients professionally and preparing these samples to be analyzed in the Units.
- Analyzing Microbiological, Biochemical and Hematological tests which are available in Branch units.
- Reviewing and signing patients' results.
- Delivering laboratories results and answering any Technical Inquiries.
- Interviewing patients & reassuring them.
- Replying to doctors' inquiries.